Finding Aid for Richard I. Ford papers, 1968-2005
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Legal Consultations
  - Zuni Case Files
    - Reports (Box 13)
      - Preliminary Report on Damage to Zuni Trust Land by E. Richard Hart (Box 13)
      - Jemez Cave and Its Place in an Early Horticultural Settlement Pattern by Richard I. Ford, 1968 (Box 13)
      - Re-excavation of the Jemez Cave, New Mexico by Richard I. Ford (Box 13)
      - Rebuttal Report: Zuni Land Use and Damage to Trust Land, DRAFT by Richard I. Ford, 1988, 2 folders (Box 13)
      - Zuni Trade by E. Richard Hart, 1979 (Box 13)
    - Research
      - Notes (Box 13)
      - Interviews, 5 folders (Box 13)
      - Maps and Surveys, 3 folders (Box 13)
      - Primary Sources, 2 folders (Box 13)
      - Photographs (Box 13)
    - Court Filings
      - Complaint (Box 13)
      - Pretrial Materials (Box 13)
      - United States Court of Claims Order (Box 13)
      - Defendant's Interrogatories to Plaintiff (Box 13)
      - Plaintiff's Interrogatories (Box 13)
      - Depositions
        - Bowannie, Belle (Box 14)
        - Bowannie, Fred (Box 14)
        - Calavaza, Clarence (Box 14)
        - Eriacho, Sefferino (Box 14)
        - Eustace, Calvin (Box 14)
        - Ghaccu, Frank (Box 14)
        - Harker, Mazone (Box 14)
        - Idiaque, Tom (Box 14)
        - Kanteena, Dempsy (Box 14)
        - Lewis, Robert Edward (Box 14)
        - Mahooty, Chester (Box 14)
        - Neumayah, Sidney (Box 14)
        - Ondelacy, Pacque (Box 14)
        - Ondelacy, Sol (Box 14)
        - Panteah, Lowell (Box 14)
        - Pinto, Ella (Box 14)
        - Potter, Loren D. (Box 14)
        - Telsee, Kathlutah (Box 14)
        - Tsabetsaye, Joe (Box 14)
        - Vacit, Frank (Box 14)
        - Walela, Bob (Box 14)
        - Wessel, Thomas R. (Box 14)
      - Plaintiff's Exhibits
        - Analysis of Photographs of Zuni Pueblo and Environment, Richard I. Ford, 1988 (Box 14)
        - Historic Photographs, James I. Ebert, 1988 (Box 14)
        - Photographic Exhibits Changes in Geomorphology, Hydrology, and Land Use on the Zuni Indian Reservation, McKinley and Cibola Counties, NM 1846-1985, Geoscience Consultants, 2 volumes (Box 14)
        - Zuni Land Use and Damage to Trust Land, Richard I. Ford, 1985 (Box 15)
        - The Zuni Mountains: Chronology of an Environmental Disaster, E. Richard Hart, 1988 (Box 15)
        - Patterns of Land Use within a Portion of the Pueblo of Zuni Land Claim Area, John O. Baxter, 1988 (Box 15)
        - Zuni Agricultural Fields Pilot Study Data Dictionary, Environmental Systems Research Institute, Inc., 1988 (Box 15)
        - The Changing Meanings of Arroyo, Samuel C. Monson, 1988 Review and Discussion of Certain Statements Concerning Oral History Contained in the Testimony of Thomas R. Wessel, Andrew Wiget, 1987 (Box 15)
        - Present and Past Climate of the Zuni Region, Martin Rose, 1985 (Box 15)
        - Patterns of Land Use and Environmental Change on the Zuni Indian Reservation, 1846-1985, T.J. Ferguson, 1985 (Box 15)
        - Letter from Patricia Nelson Limerick 1988 (Box 15)
        - Rebuttal Reports
          - Geomorphology, Hydrology, and Land Use on the Zuni Indian Reservation 1846-1988, Geoscience Consultants, Ltd., 1988 (Box 15)
          - Land Use and Land Damage on the Zuni Indian Reservation, 1846-1988, T.J. Ferguson, 1988 (Box 15)
          - Present and Past Climate of the Zuni Region, Martin Rose, 1989 (Box 15)
          - Interpretation of Historical and Contemporary Photographs, T.J. Fergus and E. Richard Hart, 1988, 2 volumes (Box 15)
          - Dendrochronological Dating of Floodplain Erosion on Zuni Indian Lands, Jeffrey S. Dean, 1989 (Box 15)
          - Erosion of Zuni Indian Reservation Lands, Stephen A. Hall, 1988 (Box 15)
        - Rebuttal Reports
          - Damage to Zuni Trust Lands, E. Richard Hart, 1988, 5 volumes (Box 16)
          - Zuni Land Use and Damage to Trust Land, Richard I. Ford, 1988, 3 volumes (Box 16)
      - Defendant's Exhibits
        - Exhibits and Bibliography, Ecological Interpretations of the Zuni Reservation, NM, Loren D. Potter (Box 16)
        - Federal Government Activity on the Zuni Reservation, Thomas R. Wessel (Box 16)
        - Analysis of Changes in Hydrology, Hydraulics, and Sediment Transport Zuni Reservation, New Mexico, Resource Consultants, Inc., 1987 (Box 16)
        - Dedrochronological Investigation of the Zuni Indian Reservation Gordon C. Jacoby, 1987 (Box 16)
        - Analysis of Zuni Indian Reservation Precipitation Patterns During the Period of Instrumental Record, Robert C. Balling, 1987 (Box 16)
        - Range Management on the Zuni Indian Reservation 1846-1946, Thadis W. Box, 1987 (Box 16)
        - A Quantitative Analysis of Arroyo Development and Geomorphic Processes in the Zuni River Drainage Basin, West-Central New Mexico, Stephen G. Wells, 1987, 2 volumes (Box 16)
        - Interdisciplinary Report-Logging Issues Zuni River/Zuni Mountain Watershed, New Mexico, 1990 (Box 17)
    - Audio Tapes
      - Babiloo, Neoma (Box 17)
      - Besalenta, Letsa (Box 17)
      - Bowannie, Belle (Box 17)
      - Bowannie, Fred (Box 17)
      - Calavasa, Clarence (Box 17)
      - Chuyate, Amy (Box 17)
      - Enote, Rita (Box 17)
      - Eriacho, Sefferino, 2 tapes (Box 17)
      - Gaspar, Chester (Box 17)
      - Gaspar, Rose and Ojo Caliente (Box 17)
      - Gjahate, Silas (Box 17)
      - Kaaymasee, Letse, 2 tapes (Box 17)
      - Kaskalla, Scotty and Paterson Peynetsa (Box 17)
      - Ladd, Ed (Box 17)
      - Lasilute, Edison and Chester Mahooty, 1 audiocassettes microcassettes (Box 17)
      - Lasiloo, Lidaneta and Malcolm Bowekety (Box 17)
      - Lasiloo, Pesancio, 2 tapes; 1 audiocassettes microcassettes (Box 17)
      - Mahooty, Chester, 3 tapes (Box 17)
      - Mateya, David (Box 17)
      - Nampeyo, Daisy (Box 17)
      - Natechu, Alta (Box 17)
      - Ondelacy, Sol, 4 tapes (Box 17)
      - Peena, May (Box 17)
      - Pekatewa, LaVerne, 3 tapes (Box 17)
      - Pesango, 1 audiocassettes microcassettes (Box 17)
      - Peynetsa, Dennis (Box 17)
      - Poblano, Mary and Ojo Caliente (Box 17)
      - Poblano, Sam and Chester and Rose Gaspar (Box 17)
      - Poncho, Ethel and Ella Pinto (Box 17)
      - Quam, Dallas, 2 tapes (Box 17)
      - Simplicio, Chauncy, 3 tapes (Box 17)
      - Tsipa, Sadie, and Meda Waikanema (Box 17)
      - Vacit, Frank, 2 tapes (Box 17)
      - Wytsalucy, Francis and Lettie Canoyoka (Box 17)
      - Zuni, Joe (Box 17)
      - Zuni Senior Center (Box 17)
- Research, Publications, and Projects
  Records in the Research, Publications, and Projects series, 1969-2002 (2.5 linear feet), document Ford's research activities in Mexico and the American Southwest. The series is divided into three subseries: projects, including grants; publications, as well as publications-related correspondence; and research. The series includes materials such as research and field notes, grant applications, papers, articles, and manuscript materials.
  - Projects
    - General (Box 18)
      - Arroyo Honda Project 1989-1990 (Box 18)
      - Art Field School 1997 (Box 18)
      - Black Mesa Archaeological Project 1980-1984, 2 folders (Box 18)
      - "Corn and Culture" Film Project 1987-1992 (Box 18)
      - Jones, Volney H. Festschrift and Celebration 1977-1979, 3 folders (Box 18)
      - Michigamua Inventory, University of Michigan 2000 (Box 18)
      - Mexico-North Research Network 1998 (Box 18)
      - Museum of Northern Arizona (Box 18)
      - National Institute for the Environment 1994 (Box 18)
      - Rappaport, Roy A. "Skip" Celebration 1998 (Box 18)
      - Reanalysis of Cucurbits in the Ethnobotanical Laboratory 1986 (Box 18)
      - School of Natural Resources and Environment, Restoration Workshop, University of Michigan 1996 (Box 18)
      - Smithsonian National Museum of Natural History, "Seeds of Change" Exhibition 1988 (Box 18)
      - "Who Owns the Past?" Film Project 1995 (Box 18)
    - Grants
      - American Council of Learned Societies, Yugoslavia Travel Grant 1971 (Box 18)
      - H. John Heinz III Charitable Trust 1986-1988 (Box 18)
      - Historical Research Associates, Pueblo Grant Proposal 1996 (Box 18)
      - Margaret Cullinan Wray Charitable Lead Annuity Trust Grant 1990 (Box 18)
      - National Endowment for the Humanities, Enhancing Access to North American Archaeological Collections (prepared by Nancy Bartlett of the Bentley Historical Library) 2001 (Box 18)
      - National Endowment for the Humanities Fellowships 1985-1986 (Box 18)
      - National Science Foundation Flotation Grant 1975-1976 (Box 18)
      - National Science Foundation Grant Awarded to Stephen E. Plog 1974 (Box 18)
      - National Science Foundation Grant Awarded to Wilma Koschik 1972 (Box 18)
      - National Science Foundation, General 1975 (Box 18)
      - National Science Foundation, Industrial Equipment Grant 1972 (Box 18)
      - National Science Foundation, Undergraduate Research Participation Grant Extension 1973 (Box 18)
      - National Science Foundation, Undergraduate Research Participation Grants 1970-1972 (Box 18)
      - National Science Foundation, University of Michigan Museum of Anthropology Grants 1971-1975 (Box 18)
      - United States Department of Agriculture, Ethnobotany Grant,1997 (Box 18)
      - University of Cincinnati Faculty Research Grant 1968 (Box 18)
      - University of Cincinnati Title VI Grant 1969 (Box 18)
      - University of Michigan Memorial-Phoenix Project Faculty Research Grant 1999 (Box 18)
      - University of Michigan, Institute for Research on Women and Gender 1998 (Box 18)
  - Publications
    - Correspondence
      - American Indian Art Magazine 1982-1984 (Box 19)
      - Cultural Ecology Textbook Contract 1971 (Box 19)
      - General Correspondence 1970-1985 (Box 19)
      - North American Indian Reprint Series, Arno Press 1980-1986 (Box 19)
      - Plants and People in Native North America 1993 (Box 19)
      - The Forgotten Undergraduate 1998 (Box 19)
      - Zuni Breadstuff, Annotations 1989 (Box 19)
    - Papers, Articles, and Books
      - "Agriculture: An Introduction," Richard I. Ford, in Paul E. Minnis, ed. Ethnobotany: A Reader, 2000 (Box 19)
      - "Analysis of the 1998 Gachupin-Brackett Canyon Plant Productivity Survey," Richard I. Ford and Robin C.D. Currey, undated
      - "Anthropological Perspectives of Ethnobotany in the Greater Southwest," Richard I. Ford Economic Botany, reprint, 1991 (Box 19)
      - "An Archaeological Survey of the Richardson Property, Black Mesa, New Mexico: A Pilot Project," Richard I. Ford 2002 (Box 19)
      - "The Archaeological Reconstruction of Human Diets," Richard I. Ford, Joint Nutrition Meeting 1986 (Box 19)
      - "Archaeology Serving Humanity," Richard I. Ford, in Charles L. Redman Research and Theory in Current Archaeology, 1973 (Box 19)
      - "Coprolite Evidence for Prehistoric Foodstuffs, Condiments, and Medicines," Richard I. Ford, Heather B. Trigg, John G. Moore, and Louise D. Jessop, in Nina Etkin, ed. Eating on the Wild Side, 1994 (Box 19)
      - "Corn Mother, Sun Father: Ecological Relationships on the Hopi Mesas," Richard I. Ford 1982 (Box 19)
      - "Don't Walk on the Grass! Ethnobotany in Middle America," Richard I. Ford undated (Box 19)
      - "An Ecological Analysis Involving the Population of San Juan Pueblo, New Mexico," Richard I. Ford, in Outstanding Dissertations on North American Indians, undated (Box 19)
      - "Ecological Consequences of Early Agriculture in the Southwest," Richard I. Ford undated (Box 19)
      - "Ecological Explanation and the Evolution of Ecosystems in the Eastern United States," Richard I. Ford 1970 (Box 19)
      - "An Ecological Perspective on the Eastern Pueblos," Richard I. Ford, in Alfonso Ortiz, ed. New Perspectives on the Pueblos, 1972 (Box 19)
      - "Ethics and the Museum Archaeologist," Richard I. Ford undated (Box 19)
      - An Ethnobiological Source Book, Richard I. Ford, Published as An Ethnobiology Source Book, 1985 (Box 19)
      - Ethnobotany in Native America, Richard I. Ford, undated (Box 19)
      - "Ethnoecology serving the community: a case study from Zuni Pueblo, New Mexico," Richard I. Ford, in Virginia Nazarea, ed. Ethnoecology: Situated Knowledge/Located Lives, 1999 (Box 19)
      - The Ethnographic American Southwest: A Source Book, Richard I. Ford, 1985 (Box 19)
      - "Fighting for the Last Archaeological Frontier," Richard I. Ford, Review of James E. Snead Ruins and Rivals, in El Palacio, 2002 (Box 19)
      - "Foreword," Richard I. Ford, in Mischa Titiev Old Oraibi: A Study of the Hopi Indians of the Third Mesa, 1992 reprint (Box 19)
      - "Foreword," Richard I. Ford, in Annual Report Native American Cultural Resources Studies Yucca Mountain, Nevada, 1988 (Box 19)
      - "From Cultivation to Domestication: A Century of Speculation," Richard I. Ford undated (Box 19)
      - "Gardening and Farming Before A.D. 1000 Patterns of Prehistoric Cultivation North of Mexico," Richard I. Ford, undated (Box 19)
      - "Health Views and Practices Among Early Wisconsin Indians," Richard I. Ford 1976 (Box 19)
      - "Human Disturbance and Biodiversity: A Case Study from Northern New Mexico," Richard I. Ford, in Minnis and Elisens, eds. Biodiversity and Native America, 2000 (Box 19)
      - "Immigration, Irrigation, and Warfare--Some Thoughts," Richard I. Ford 1969 (Box 19)
      - "The Intellectual Basis of Paleoethnobotany in the Southeast," Richard I. Ford, Southeast Archaeological Conference 1988 (Box 19)
      - "Inter-Indian Exchange," Richard I. Ford, in William C. Sturtevant, ed. Handbook of North American Indians, 1973 (Box 19)
      - "The Introduction of the Spanish Plant Complex Into Florida, Mexico, and the American Southwest," Richard I. Ford, Joint conference of the Society for Economic Botany and the International Society for Ethnopharmacology 1996 (Box 19)
      - "James Bennett Griffin, 1905-1997" Richard I. Ford American Anthropologist, 2001 (Box 19)
      - Man and His Foods, ed. C. Earl Smith, Jr., Reviewed by Richard I. Ford, 1973 (Box 19)
      - "Northeastern Archaeology: Past and Future Directions," Richard I. Ford Annual Review of Anthropology, 1974 (Box 19)
      - "Nuts for Hopewellians," Richard I. Ford undated (Box 19)
      - "One Hundred Years of Ethnobotany," Richard I. Ford undated (Box 19)
      - "Origins of Agriculture in Native North America," Richard I. Ford 1971, 2 folders (Box 19)
      - "Origins of Husbandry," Richard I. Ford, Review of Erich Isaac Geography of Domestication, in Science, 1972 (Box 19)
      - "Paleoethnobotany I," Richard I. Ford and Naomi Miller, in John H. Humphrey, ed. Excavations at Carthage Conducted by the University of Michigan, 1978 (Box 19)
      - "Paleoethnobotany in American Archaeology," Richard I. Ford, in Michael B. Schiffer Advances in Archaeological Method and Theory v. 2, 1979 (Box 19)
      - The Paleoethnobotany of the Koster Site, Richard I. Ford and Nancy B. Asch, 1972 (Box 19)
      - "Pots, Politics, and Professions," Richard I. Ford, undated"The Power of Land, the Spirit in Plants," Richard I. Ford undated (Box 19)
      - The Prehistoric American Southwest: A Source Book: Four Historical Themes: History, Chronology, Ecology, Technology, Richard I. Ford, 1987 (Box 19)
      - "Prehistoric Subsistence," Richard I. Ford Quarterly Review of Archaeology, 1989 (Box 19)
      - "The Processes of Plant Food Production in Prehistoric North America," Richard I. Ford, in Richard I. Ford, ed. Prehistoric Food Production in North America, 1985 (Box 19)
      - "A Productivity Study of Teosinte (Zea Mexicana)," Richard I. Ford and Kent V. Flannery 1971 (Box 19)
      - "Recorded Rock Art Sites on Black Mesa, New Mexico: A Summary and Assessment," Richard I. Ford 2002 (Box 19)
      - Reference Outline and Bibliography of Settlement Pattern Studies, Richard I. Ford undated (Box 19)
      - "Report to the Representative to the AAS," Richard I. Ford American Antiquity, 1973 (Box 19)
      - "Salvaging Biological Remains from Archaeological Sites," Richard I. Ford undated (Box 19)
      - "Science in Native America," Richard I. Ford undated (Box 19)
      - "A Selected Ethnobotanical Bibliography," Richard I. Ford undated (Box 19)
      - "The Technology of Irrigation in a New Mexico Pueblo," Richard I. Ford, in Heather Lechtman and Robert Merrill, eds. Material Culture: Styles, Organization and Dynamics of Technology, 1977 (Box 19)
      - "Teotihuacan Paleoethnobotany," Richard I. Ford, Society for American Archaeology 1972 (Box 19)
      - "With Roots in Mexico: Prehistoric Agricultural Connections," Richard I. Ford Early Man Magazine, 1981 (Box 19)
  - Research
    - Biodiversity 1993 (Box 20)
    - Cienigilla Historic New Mexico 1986 (Box 20)
    - Ethnobotanical Information Systems 1997 (Box 20)
    - Oaxaca Market Survey 1972 (Box 20)
    - Permits 1995 (Box 20)
    - Research Notes 1973 (Box 20)
    - Schultz Site 20a-2, Field Notes 1964 (Box 20)
- Professional Service and Activities
  Materials in the Professional Service and Activities series, 1968-2004 (4.5 linear feet), are further divided into five subseries: committees, societies and organizations, independent conferences, lectures, and reviews. The committees subseries documents Ford's administrative involvement with and on committees and boards at the University of Michigan and beyond. The societies and organizations subseries chronicles Ford's work with professional bodies such as the American Anthropology Association, the American Association for the Advancement of Science, the Conference on Michigan Archaeology, and the Society for American Archaeology. The series also includes the subseries independent conferences, which contains records from conferences Ford attended that were not affiliated with a professional body, but rather another type of institution, such as a university or museum. The lectures subseries includes correspondence and writings from lectures delivered by Ford. The final subseries, reviews, documents Ford's work as an editorial reviewer, member of external review panels for cultural institutions and universities, and as a participant in tenure and promotion reviews.
  - Committees
    - Archaeological Conservancy Executive Committee Meeting 1988, 3 folders (Box 20)
    - Central Committee on the Undergraduate Curriculum Advisory Group 1991-1996 (Box 20)
    - Ethnobotany Commission 1968-1989 (Box 20)
    - Gateway Campus Planning Committee 1992-1993 (Box 20)
    - Literature Science and the Arts Visiting Committee 1991 (Box 20)
    - National Endowment for the Humanities Review Panel 1987-1988 (Box 20)
    - National Science Foundation Advisory Panel 1971-1979 (Box 20)
    - Native American Study Steering Committee 1982-1984 (Box 20)
    - Nomination Committee, Rould Fryxell Award, Chairman 1979-1980 (Box 20)
    - Pew Higher Education Roundtable 1994-1995, 3 folders (Box 20)
    - President's Advisory Group on Planning 1991 (Box 20)
    - Provost and Executive Vice President for Academic Affairs Search (Box 20)
    - Advisory Committee 1989-1997 (Box 20)
    - Provost Arts Advisory Committee 1998-1999 (Box 20)
    - Senate Assembly Research Policies Committee 1999, 4 folders (Box 21)
    - VCM Oversight Committee 1997-1998 (Box 21)
    - Walpi Advisory Panel 1979-1981, 2 folders (Box 21)
  - Societies and Organizations
    - American Anthropology Association
      - Archaeology Division 1988-1991, 8 folders (Box 21)
      - Awards 1991 (Box 21)
      - Chairmanship,1989 1991, 2 folders (Box 21)
      - Division Head,1991 (Box 21)
      - Employment Workshop 2001 (Box 21)
      - Executive Director Search 1996 (Box 21)
      - Phoenix Meeting 1988 (Box 21)
      - Reorganization 1979-1993, 4 folders (Box 21)
      - Symposium 1991 (Box 22)
      - Washington Meeting 1995 (Box 22)
    - American Association for the Advancement of Science
      - Chair, Section H 1987-1988, 2 folders (Box 22)
    - Denver 1977 (Box 22)
    - American Association for Museums 1984 (Box 22)
    - American Ethnological Association, Detroit, Michigan 1975 (Box 22)
    - Baca Institute for Ethnobotany 1994-1997 (Box 22)
    - Material Culture: Styles, Organization and Dynamics of Technology (Box 22)
    - American Indian Historical Society 1970 (Box 22)
    - Central States Anthropological Association, Detroit 1971 (Box 22)
    - Conference on Michigan Archaeology 1969-1974, 2 folders (Box 22)
    - Congress of Americanists, Manchester, England 1982 (Box 22)
    - International Botanical Conference 1981 (Box 22)
    - International Society for Ethnobiology
      - Cambridge, Massachusetts 1985 (Box 22)
      - Lucknow, India 1994 (Box 22)
    - International Congress of Anthropological and Ethnological Sciences, Vancouver and Quebec 1982 (Box 22)
    - International Congress of Ethnobiology
      - Brazil 1988 (Box 22)
      - General 1990, 2000 (Box 22)
      - Mexico City 1994 (Box 22)
    - National Endowment for the Humanities 1990 (Box 22)
    - National Institute for the Conservation of Cultural Property 1983-1989, 2 folders (Box 22)
    - Ohio Humanities Council, Columbus, Ohio 1988 (Box 22)
    - Society for American Archaeology
      - Administrative Reports 1970-1978 (Box 22)
      - General 1969-1985 (Box 22)
      - Las Vegas, Small Sites 1990 (Box 22)
      - Minneapolis 1982 (Box 22)
      - San Francisco 1973 (Box 22)
      - St. Louis (Box 22)
      - Seeds to Gardens: Topics in Plains Ethnobotany 1993 (Box 22)
      - Is There a Future in Archaeology? 1992 (Box 22)
      - Tucson, Arizona 1978 (Box 22)
    - Vancouver, Canada, Curation of Archaeological Collections 1979 (Box 23)
    - Society for Economic Botany, College Station
      - General 1989-1992, 2 folders (Box 23)
      - General 1996 (Box 23)
      - Texas 1984 (Box 23)
    - Society for Ethnobotany 1990 (Box 23)
    - Southeastern Indian Antiquities Survey 1970-1971 (Box 23)
    - Southwestern Anthropological Association, Santa Fe 1975 (Box 23)
  - Independent Conferences
    - Botanical Society of America and the American Institute for Biological Sciences, Current Thought in Plant Ecology, "Ethnobotany and Ecology: A Synthesis," 1973
    - Carnegie Museum of Natural History, The Cultural Emergence of Man, "Early Domestication in the New World," 1979 (Box 23)
    - Hopewell Conference, "Gathering and Gardening: Trends and Consequences of Hopewell Subsistence Strategies," 1978 (Box 23)
    - Monticello-University of Virginia, Conference on Landscape Archaeology, "Ethnoscience, Archaeobotany, and the Reconstruction of an Anthropogenic Landscape," 1986 (Box 23)
    - New York Academy of Sciences, Research Potential of Museum Collections, "New Ideas about the Origin of Agriculture Based on 50 Years of Museum Curated Plant Remains," 1981 (Box 23)
    - University of Michigan
      - Center for South and Southeast Asian Studies, Ecology and Evolution in the Tropics, "Agriculture and Evolution: Enabling or Inevitable?," 1986 (Box 23)
      - Journal of Law Reform, Symposium: The Preservation of Minority Cultures, "Whose Culture Is It? Repatriation of Native American Heritage," 1992, 2 folders (Box 23)
      - University of Michigan and the Smithsonian Institution, Presenting History: Museums in a Democratic Society 1995 (Box 23)
    - University of Minnesota, Corn and Culture in the Prehistoric New World, "Corn is Our Mother," 1990 (Box 23)
    - University of New Mexico, New Perspectives on the Pueblos, "Perspectives on New Mexican Prehistory," 1971 (Box 23)
    - University of Pennsylvania, University Museum: Assets or Liabilities?, "The Collections and Student Use," 1980 (Box 23)
    - Recursos of Santa Fe, Gardens of the Southwest, "Impact of Spanish Foods on Pueblo Diet and Gardens," 1991 (Box 23)